《アハハハ…》
（英梨々）《アハ…》
《わあ～》
（英梨々）ん～。
（英梨々）《ウフフ…》
（倫也）《あっ。　ハハハ》
（英梨々）暑…。
《フフフ》
（英梨々）《ウフフ》
（児童たち）《お～　お～　お～…》
Little Love Rhapsody
It's hot.
Whenever we're together in the classroom after school
houkago futari de sugoshita kyoushitsu
You at your desk, just talking and talking on and on
tsukue no ue muchuu de hazumu kimi no koe
You're so dense, and it really shows
donkan na kimi no sono taido ga
And that's why I always have to pick on you
itsumo watashi wo ijiwaru ni saseru no
Sometimes I feel like I'm alone
hitoribocchi da to omou toki mo aru
Some days I can't stop myself from crying
namida tomerarenai hi mo aru
I want you to look and see the real me
hontou no watashi wo mitsumete hoshii no
I'll keep believing that one day you will
kitto tsutawaru to shinjiteiru yo
But you just never, ever, never, ever change, and so
kimi wa itsudatte itsudatte kawaranai kara
I keep sending and sending and sending and sending the same signal
watashi ga nankai mo nankai mo signal okutteageru
Dreaming of the day I'll make it over that hill
yume mita ano oka mezashite
Even when I feel like giving up, I can keep going on
kujikesou na toki mo ganbaresou da yo
Because you're there for me
kimi ga iru kara
Uh, wasn't today's circle meeting supposed to be for working on character designs?
（恵）…で　確か
今日のサークル活動は→
A Teased and Abandoned Girl's Trauma Recollection Mode
キャラクターデザインの方向性の
打ち合わせだったよね？
（倫也）ああ。　特に　加藤が
モデルとなるメインヒロインのな。
Yeah, particularly for the main heroine we're going to base on you, Katou.
私　脱ぐなんて　聞いてないよ。
Nobody said anything about
me taking my clothes off!
安心しろ　加藤。
そっちは　ゲームの絵じゃない。
Don't worry, Katou. These aren't for our game.
英梨々のサークルの
夏コミ原稿だ。
This is the manuscript for Eriri's
circle's Summer Comiket book.
（英梨々）ごめんなさいね
加藤さん。
Sorry about this, Katou-san.
ちょっとだけ
スケジュール　押しちゃって。
I'm a little behind schedule.
O-Oh, I see.
へ…　へえ　そうなんだ。
大変だね。→
Sounds rough.
その夏コミって　いつからだっけ？
So when does Summer Comiket start?
あしたから。
（恵）えっ？
Tomorrow.
What?
あしたから。
（恵）えっと→
Um, and you're yet to print the books?
今から　印刷するんだよね？
大丈夫
コミケは　３日間もあるの。
We'll be fine. Comiket runs for three days.
あたしのサークルは
最終日だから　余裕よ。
My circle will be there on the third,
so it's not a problem.
It's not?
そうなの？
んなわけねーだろ！
Like hell it's not!
Not only will there be a surcharge tacked onto the printing fee,
印刷代に
特別料金が上乗せされる上に→
but making the print shop work during their Bon vacation is the worst thing you can do!
印刷所の皆さんの
お盆休みを奪う　最悪の行為だ。
せっかく　ネーム
手伝ってやったのに。
I even helped out with your storyboards,
so why are you still working at the last minute?!
何で　こんな　ぎりぎりまで
引っ張ってんだよ？
One does not simply explain why
an author is late with a manuscript.
（英梨々）作家が
原稿　遅らせることに→
理由なんてないのよ。
Oh, that was kind of cool.
あっ　何か　カッコイイ。
んなわけねーだろ！
Like hell it was!
（恵）にしても　コミケかぁ。
いよいよだね。
Still, Comiket's finally here, huh?
ああ　いよいよだ。
Yeah, finally.
だが　今回の夏コミは
あくまで前哨戦。
But remember, this Comiket is nothing
more than an opening skirmish.
俺たちの真の戦いは
年末の冬コミ。
Our true battle will be Winter Comiket
at the end of the year!
デビュー作となる
超大作ギャルゲーを引っ提げ→
I'll march in with my blockbuster debut
dating sim and revolutionize the doujin world,
同人界に革命を起こす
スーパープロデューサー＆ディレクター→
marking the beginning of the legend of
super producer-slash-director, Aki Tomoya!
安芸　倫也の　伝説の幕開けが。
Come to think of it, are you going to be there, Sawamura-san?
そういえば　澤村さんは
行くんだよね？
自分の本　出すんだし。
After all, you're releasing your book there.
Of course not.
行くわけないじゃない。　売り子は
パパとママに任せてあるわよ。
I'm having my mom and dad man my table.
ずいぶんと理解のあるご両親だね。
You must have awfully understanding parents.
あなたは　行くつもりなの？
Are you planning to go?
A civilian like you is gonna regret casually strolling onto that battlefield, the world's largest gathering of otaku.
あんな
世界一　オタクが集まる戦場に→
一般人が軽い気持ちで近づいたら
後悔するわよ。
でも　せっかく　出海ちゃんに
チケット　もらったし→
But I've already been given
a ticket from Izumi-chan,
and I thought it could be a kind of rehearsal for the end of the year.
年末のリハーサルのつもりで
行ってみようかなって…。
I'm really looking forward to
seeing Izumi-chan's doujinshi.
楽しみだよね。
出海ちゃんの同人誌。
ああ。　あの熱の入れようだと→
Yeah. Considering the enthusiasm she has for it,
きっと　『リトラプ』愛にあふれた
楽しい本になってんだろうなあ。
I bet it'll be a fun book brimming
with her love for LitRhap!
まあ　ぜいたくは言わないから
こういう本じゃないことを祈るよ。
Well, I'm not expecting too much.
I just pray it won't be like this book.
ああ　それなら大丈夫だぞ。
Oh, you don't have to worry about that.
Even an 18+ LitRhap book probably
wouldn't have any female nudity in it.
『リトラプ』本なら
１８禁だったとしても→
たぶん　女の子の裸は
出てこないから。
What kind of nudity will it have, then?
Is this really okay?
それって　何の裸が出てくるの？
本当に大丈夫なの？
Are you sure you want to play this game?
本当に　このゲームでいいのか？
だって　ほら　出海ちゃん→
Well, Izumi-chan said it was really fun,
so my curiosity's kinda been piqued.
ものすっごく面白いって
言ってたし→
ちょっと
興味　湧いちゃったんだよね。
Izumi-chan was raving about LitRhap 3, though.
出海ちゃんが　熱く語ってたのは
『リトラプ３』だけど→
New Game
Little Love Rhapsody
Load Game
Settings
これは　１作目だぞ。
This one's the first game.
Well, you don't have 3 here, so this'll have to do.
（恵）ここに　『３』がないんだから
仕方ないよ。
New Game
Little Love Rhapsody
Load Game
Settings
New Game
Besides, isn't it better to start off with the first entry in the series?
それに　どうせなら最初の作品から触れてみるのも　いいよね？
Now you're wanting to play
dating sims of your own will.
いつの間にか　自分の意思で
乙女ゲーをプレーしたいと→
言いだすなんて。
Katou! You've grown up as an otaku so fast!
加藤。
お前　オタクとして成長したな。
Uh, yeah, I guess so.
ああ　うん。　そうだね。
Megumi
って　いきなり　本名プレー！？
You're jumping right in with your own name?!
覚悟　決め過ぎだろ！
That's getting way too into it!
Not even I could do something that embarrassing!
俺だって　なかなか　できないぞ。
そんな恥ずかしいまね。
安芸君は
もう　作業に戻っていいよ。
You can get back to work, Aki-kun.
I'll just pass the time here.
私　勝手に
時間　つぶしてるから。
おっ　おう。
R-Right.
英梨々。
Eriri?
何よ。
What?
Well, you making progress?
いや　お前…　原稿は？
うっ…　ほんのちょっと
休憩してただけじゃない。
I was just taking a little break, that's all!
いちいち　細かいこと言って
うざいわね！
You're so annoying, constantly
nitpicking every little thing!
Am I now?
そうですか。　お前の原稿に
理不尽に付き合わされてる俺が→
Well I'm sorry that I, the one you're forcing to help with your manuscript for some crazy reason, am annoying.
うざいですか。　ごめんなさい。
（恵）あれ？　キャラ選択だ。
Oh, I have to select a character.
Blind Minstrel
Neighbouring Kingdom Prince
Childhood Friend
Step Brother
Blind Minstrel
Neighbouring Kingdom Prince
Childhood Friend
Step Brother
Symphonne
Jeas
Servis
Erral
Yep. This is where you choose your
knight attendant who'll keep watch over you.
そう。　ここで
自分の身の回りの警備をする→
お付きの騎士を選ぶんだ。
By the way, once you choose, you'll only get events centered around that character for the first month,
ちなみに　選んだら　１カ月間は→
そのキャラに関連した
イベントしか　起きないから。
慎重な選択が必要にだな…。
so you need to choose carefully.
I'll be fine, Aki-kun.
大丈夫だよ　安芸君。
I'm reading the guide as I go.
ちゃんと　マニュアル　読みながら
進めてるから。
I see.
そうか…。
ん～　誰にしようかな…。
Who should I pick?
えっと…　エラルお兄さまに
ジーアス王子に→
So, there's Erral-oniisama,
Prince Jeas, and Symphonne-sama.
シンフォーニュさま？→
あっ　この幼なじみの
セルビスにしようっと。
Oh, I think I'll go with the childhood friend, Servis.
Blind Minstrel
Neighbouring Kingdom Prince
Childhood Friend
Step Brother
Servis
Symphonne
Jeas
Servis
Erral
Childhood Friend
Confirm
Blind Minstrel
Childhood Friend
Step Brother
Servis
Symphonne
Jeas
Servis
Childhood Friend
Cancel
Servis
Childhood Friend
Blind Minstrel
Symphonne
Jeas
Servis
Childhood Friend
Confirm
Jeas
Servis
Blind Minstrel
Confirm
Cancel
Servis
Symphonne
Childhood Friend
Jeas
Servis
Childhood Friend
Jeas
Servis
Childhood Friend
Jeas
Servis
Childhood Friend
Jeas
Servis
Childhood Friend
Jeas
Servis
Childhood Friend
Jeas
Servis
Childhood Friend
Jeas
Servis
Childhood Friend
Jeas
Servis
セルビス　選んじゃったの！？
You picked Servis?!
い…　いえ
駄目ってわけじゃないんだけど→
Uh, I'm not telling you not to...
フラグ管理が　とても　難しくて→
but his flags are really hard to manage and
he has pretty specific hidden event triggers.
隠しイベントの発生条件が
かなり特殊な→
上級者向けキャラなんだけどな…。
He's geared towards more advanced players.
あのね　だからね　澤村さん…。
As I said earlier, I'll be fine, Sawamura-san.
そういえば　お前
前から　セルビス推しだったな。
Come to think of it, you've always been a Servis fan, haven't you?
The fireworks sure are beautiful.
Servis
For you, I've always...
Megumi, for you, I've always...
（恵）どうしよう　安芸君。
何て答えよう。
What should I do, Aki-kun?
How should I answer?
俺に聞くなよ　恵！
Don't ask me, "Megumi"!
But like, this confession seems really intense.
だってさ　この告白は重いよ。
ギャルゲーも　乙女ゲーも
一度　告白を受け入れたら最後→
In dating sims, once you accept a confession of love, that's it.
あとは　永遠の愛　一直線だ。
After that, it's a straight line to eternal love.
Servis
The fireworks sure are beautiful.
Megumi, for you, I've always...
浮気や心変わりなんて
許されないぞ。
You won't be able to cheat or change your mind.
（恵）けど　私たち
まだ　高校生だし。
But we're still high schoolers.
Servis
The fireworks sure are beautiful.
Megumi, for you, I've always...
Servis
The fireworks sure are beautiful.
Megumi, for you, I've always...
Servis
The fireworks sure are beautiful.
Megumi, for you, I've always...
Servis
The fireworks sure are beautiful.
Megumi, for you, I've always...
いきなり　現実に
逃げ帰ろうとするな！
Servis
The fireworks sure are beautiful.
Megumi, for you, I've always...
Servis
The fireworks sure are beautiful.
Megumi, for you, I've always...
Servis
The fireworks sure are beautiful.
Megumi, for you, I've always...
Servis
The fireworks sure are beautiful.
Megumi, for you, I've always...
Servis
The fireworks sure are beautiful.
Megumi, for you, I've always...
Don't try to escape back to reality!
Servis
The fireworks sure are beautiful.
Megumi, for you, I've always...
澤村さんなら　どう答え…。
Sawamura-san, what would you...
ごめん。　ホント
原稿の邪魔しちゃって　ごめんね。
Sorry.
I'm really sorry for distracting
you from your manuscript.
Little Love Rhapsody
New Game
Load Game
Settings
I have to say, you're really consistent with the quality of your doujinshi.
にしても　やっぱり　安定してんな。お前の同人誌は。
（英梨々）時間がないからって
絵が荒れちゃったら→
It would be an insult to my buyers if my artwork was sloppy just because I was pressed for time.
本を買う人に失礼でしょ。
Eriri, wouldn't you be able to make
a living doing this professionally?
英梨々　お前　もう　プロでも
やっていけるんじゃないか？
商業の編集さんとか　よく
サークルスペースに来るらしいわよ。→
Apparently, industry editors
have been visiting my circle's tables.
But I never go to events, so I've never spoken to any of them in person.
私が　イベントに行かないから
直接　話したことはないけどね。
My circle is quite interested in you.
（伊織）《うちのサークルは
君に　とても興味がある》
Say, Eriri...
なあ　英梨々。
（英梨々）うん？
Yeah?
「ｒｏｕｇｅ　ｅｎ　ｒｏｕｇｅ」からの誘い
どうすんだ？
What are you going to do about
that invitation from rouge en rouge?
魅力的な話よね。
It's a tempting offer.
そうだよな。
I suppose so.
They're a popular circle, so I'd probably more than double my sales with them.
（英梨々）
シャッター前サークルだから→
きっと　今の倍以上は売れるし→
I'd be pretty much guaranteed
to become more successful.
もう　成功は
約束されたようなものよね。
英梨々は
これから　どうしたいんだ？
Where do you want to go from here?
これからって？
From here?
Will you continue to draw just
as a hobby, like you do now,
今みたいに
趣味で絵を描いていくのか→
or will you strive for something bigger?
それとも　もっと上を目指すのか。
If you say you really want to go for it, then I—
もし　お前がさ→
本気で　やっていきたいって
言うんなら　俺は…。
I'm finished!
終わった～！
うわっ。
Ever since I saw Katou-san playing, I've been itching to have a go!
（英梨々）もう　さっき　加藤さんが
プレーしてるの見てるときから→
我慢できなかったのよねー。
Load Game
Little Love Rhapsody
New Game
Settings
Load Game
Little Love Rhapsody
New Game
Settings
Load Game
うあ～　何か　イベント発生条件
全部　覚えてる。
Wow, somehow I still know all the event triggers.
何で　そんなに　慣れてんだよ。
How can you remember this so well?
And I haven't played it in 8 years.
ホント　プレーするの
８年ぶりなのにな～。
（英梨々）何でだろ…。→
I wonder why.
ねえ　覚えてる？　倫也。
Hey, do you remember, Tomoya?
About this game.
（英梨々）このゲームって…。
ああ　もともと　お前のだよ。
Oh, it used to be yours.
（英梨々）借りパクってやつよね。
You borrowed it and never returned it.
あのときは　返せなかったからな。
Well, I wasn't really able to back then.
Hey, Tomoya.
（英梨々）ねえ　倫也。
ん？
今から　あたしは→
From this moment on, I'm Kashiwagi Eri,
a member of your circle.
あんたのサークルの
柏木エリだからね。
Until Winter Comiket,
I won't be attending any events,
冬コミまでは　他のイベントにも
一切　出ないし→
and I won't be taking on any guest artist jobs.
ゲスト原稿すら
一つも請けるつもりはないからね。
So, you're saying...
お前…　それって…。
だいたい　引き抜かれるにしたって
波島になんて　ごめんよね。
Besides, even if I was gonna pull out,
it sure as hell wouldn't be for Hashima.
He's only in it for the money, discarding
creators and women when he's done with them.
あんな　作家も女も使い捨てな
最低の同人ゴロ。
いや　お前　さすがに　それは
元同級生に対して　ひどいだろ。
That's a pretty harsh thing to say
about a former classmate.
So you really like him after all, don't you?
倫也　あんた　やっぱ
波島のこと　好きでしょ？
In the way the BL fans want to see.
それも　腐女子が喜ぶレベルで。
I don't need that kind of backstory!
そんな裏設定　いらないから。
エヘヘ。
アハ…　アハハハ…。
ったく…。
Sheesh...
アハハハ…。
（恵）夜食　できたよ～。
Dinner's ready!
You two sure seem to be
getting cozy for some reason.
って　何か　いい雰囲気だね。
２人とも。
男の家で当然のように　料理
作ってる　あなたに言われると→
I'm not sure how I feel about hearing that from a girl
who just cooked dinner at a guy's house like it's nothing.
何か　微妙。
（恵）ん？
Hurry, Katou!
But don't run!
急げ　加藤。　でも　走るなよ。
The time period for circle entry is almost up!
そろそろ　サークル入場が
締め切られる時間だ。
Uh, hey, Aki-kun...
（恵）あのさ　安芸君。
何だよ？
Yes?
What's with all that?
何なの？　これ。
Surprised?
驚いたか！　ここで
後ろを振り返った人たちは→
This is the legendary stairway people look down upon
and want to shout, "Look, people are garbage!"
皆　「見ろ　人がごみのようだ」と
叫びたくなる伝説の階段だ！
伝説なのは　階段の方じゃないと
思うんだけど。
I don't think it's the stairway
itself that's legendary.
しかし　今日の俺たちは
あそこに並ぶやつらとは違う。
But today, we're not like the poor schlubs
standing in line down there!
We're circle ticketholders, chosen by the
world order that is the Planning Committee!
準備会という　世界の秩序によって選ばれた　サークルチケット組だ。
だから　遠慮なく
ごみ扱いしてもいいぞ。
So it's perfectly fine to treat them like garbage.
It's not and you know it.
（恵）よくないでしょ。
≪よっ　出海ちゃん。
Hey, Izumi-chan.
（出海）あっ。　倫也先輩！
Tomoya-senpai!
（出海）本当に
来てくれたんですね！
You really came!
そりゃ　出海ちゃんの
一世一代の晴れの舞台…。
Of course. This is a once-in-a-lifetime event for you, so how could I—
ぐふっ。
うれしい。
I'm so glad!
私…　私…。
I...
（恵）えっと…　私もいるんだけど。
Um... I came as well, you know.
You too, Senpai's girlfriend!
先輩の彼女さんも
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
（恵）えっと…　せっかく
彼女と勘違いされてることだし→
Uh, since I'm being mistaken
for his girlfriend and all...
「倫也から離れなさいよ。
この　泥棒猫」→
Get your mitts off my Tomoya, you homewrecker.
とか　言った方がいいかな？
Or I suppose that's what I should be saying.
やるなら
せめて　ほんの少しくらいは→
If you were going to play that,
you could've at least put some feeling into it.
感情　込めてくれ。
SAMPLE
お二人とも　お手伝い
ありがとうございました。
SAMPLE
Thanks so much for all your help, you two!
（恵）えっ？　もう　準備　終わり？
Huh? Is this all you're doing?
はい。
あとは　開場を待つだけです。
Yes. Now we just wait for the hall to open.
でも　あっちの人たちは
まだ　ずいぶんと忙しそうだけど。
But the people over there
seem to be working pretty hard.
あ～　アハハハ…。
加藤…。
Katou...
Huh? Did I say something wrong?
えっ？
私　何か　まずいこと言った？
あの場所に
配置されているのはな→
Circles that get placed over there are, well...
販売数も　数千レベル。
They have sales measuring in the thousands
売り上げも　数百万から
下手すれば　千万単位。
and proceeds ranging from
millions to tens of millions of yen.
They're popular spotlight circles who attract the
attention of many, including the National Tax Agency.
そんなこんなで　税務署にも
熱く注目されている→
いわゆる　超人気サークルだ。
（出海）それに比べて　こちらは→
By comparison, we'd be glad to sell even half of the
100 units we ordered with smiles always on our faces.
搬入数１００部で
半分売れれば　御の字。
いつも　にこにこ…
赤字会計　「Ｆａｎｃｙ　Ｗａｖｅ」です。
We're Fancy Wave, whose ledger is always in the red.
Oh, I see. I'm sorry, I guess.
そうなんだ。　何か　ごめんね。
まあ　コミケに参加してる
９割以上のサークルは→
Well, that's true for more than
90% of the circles participating here.
だいたい　そんな感じだけどな。
But that's perfectly fine.
いえ　そんなの　いいんです！
When it comes to selling doujinshi from a table, there's something far more important than moving lots of units!
同人誌即売会には
たくさん　売れるよりも→
大事なことがあるんだから。
（恵）あるんだ。
Really?
（出海）だって　同じ趣味の人たちが一つの場所に集って→
I mean, many people sharing a
common hobby are coming together,
showing each other their wares,
and having passionate discussions!
作品を見せ合ったり
熱く語ったりするなんて→
とっても　すてきなことだと
思いませんか？
Don't you think that's great?
So what you're saying is that
everyone here is like you and Aki-kun?
つまり　ここにいるのは　みんな→
安芸君や出海ちゃんみたいな
人たちってこと？
何だよ？
その　嫌そうなリアクション。
What's with that disgusted reaction?
Um, it's what it looks like.
えっと…　見たまんまでね。
This is a place of doujinshi, dreams, and comrades.
（出海）ここには　同人誌がある
夢がある　仲間がいる…。
There are so many wonderful things here.
すてきなことが
こんなに　いっぱい　あるんです。
（出海）私　同人誌　作り始めて
まだ　１年だけど→
I've only been making doujinshi for a year so far,
but I've had all kinds of fun experiences,
ホント　楽しいこと
色々　あったし→
これからだって
たくさんあると思うんです。
and I think there'll be many more to come.
That's why even if our books don't sell at all,
だから　たとえ
本が　全然　売れなくったって→
１人で売り子しなくちゃ
ならないから→
even if I can't go and buy from the other circles because I have to man the table on my own,
他のサークルの本も
買いに行けなくたって→
売れ残りの本で
帰りのキャリーバッグが重くったって→
and even if I have to go home
with the weight of all my unsold books,
決して泣いたりしないんです。
you can bet that I won't shed a single tear!
Izumi-chan, we're here with you today,
so feel free to go and buy some books yourself.
（恵）出海ちゃん。
今日は　私たちがいるから→
遠慮なく
本を買いに行っていいから。
はっ　はい！
ありがとうございます。　彼女さん。
Ah, of course! Thank you
very much, Miss Girlfriend!
一生　恩に着ます。
I'm forever in your debt!
You know, you can call me by my name.
あのね　私のことは　名前でいいよ。
はい　分かりました。　加茂さん！
Okay, sure thing, Kamo-san!
（恵）え～っと…。
出海ちゃん。
Uh...
Izumi-chan.
はい？
Yes?
How many years have you
been making doujinshi for?
同人誌　始めて　何年になるって？
えっ　だから　やっと１年ですよ。
Like I said, just barely one year.
それまでは　買い専で。
Up until then, I only bought them.
You drew this... after only a year?
１年で…
君は　これを描いたのか？
先輩？
Senpai?
安芸君？　大丈夫？
Aki-kun?
Are you all right?
Hey, Izumi-chan...
なあ　出海ちゃん。
About these books...
この本
完売させちゃ　まずいかな？
Would you mind if they all sold?
[ﾏｲｸ]（アナウンス）ただ今から
コミックマーケット　２日目を→
Comic Market has now opened for day two.
開会いたします。
チクショー　チクショー。
Crap! Crap!
これだから　同人誌は
やめられねえんだよな～！
This is why I can't just abandon doujinshi!
（女性）ねえ　あそこのサークル
まだ　残ってるかな～。
Hey, I wonder if that circle over there has any left.
Megumi-san?
（出海）恵さん…。→
あの…　恵さん。
Um, Megumi-san?
えっ？　ああ　ごめん。　何？
Huh? Oh, I'm sorry. What is it?
（出海）倫也先輩
どこ行っちゃったんでしょう？
Where do you suppose Tomoya-senpai went?
（恵）さあ…　でも　そのうち
帰ってくると思うよ。
No idea. But I'm sure he'll be back before long.
Aren't you worried?
（出海）気にならないんですか？
Actually it's him that isn't concerned about me.
（恵）そもそも　気にされてないのは私の方だし。
Oh, are you mad at him a bit?
（出海）あっ　ちょっと　怒ってる？
Well, you're the one Aki-kun
is working so hard for right now.
（恵）だいたい
今　安芸君が頑張ってるのって→
出海ちゃんのためだよ。
How can you know that?
Kokusai-Tenjijo Station
（出海）どうして
そんなこと　分かるんですか？→
How can you have so much faith in him?
何で　そんなに
信じられるんですか？
（恵）全然　信じてないから
分かるんだけど。
It's because I don't have
faith in him at all that I know.
（出海）あっ
また　ちょっと怒った？
Did I make you angry again?
So, uh...
（出海）あの…。
（恵）ん？　何かな？　出海ちゃん。
Yes, Izumi-chan?
Megumi-san, are you really
Tomoya-senpai's girlfriend?
（出海）恵さんって　ホントに
倫也先輩の彼女なんですか？
（恵）ううん。　メインヒロイン。
No, I'm his main heroine.
（出海）何ですか？　それ。
What does that mean?
I'd really like to know that myself.
（恵）何なんだろうね。　本当に。
≪ごめん！　遅くなった。
Sorry. I got held up.
先輩！→
Senpai!
先輩…。
Senpai...
何部　売れた？
How many have we sold?
Um... I think about 30.
（恵）えっと　３０部ぐらいかな。
ってことは　あと　７０か。
So 70 to go, then.
Easy game.
楽勝だな。
さあ　どうぞ！
ご覧になっていってくださ～い！
Come on, step right up!
Please come over and take a look!
（出海）ちょっ…
ちょっと待ってよ　先輩。
W-Wait a minute, Senpai!
何で　こんな　でかいポスター
作っちゃったんですか～。
Why did you make such a massive poster?!
Izumi-chan.
出海ちゃん。
うん？
All you said about not caring for
how much you sell was a lie, right?
売れなくてもいいなんて
嘘だよな。
SAMPLE
500YEN
You want lots of people to read this, right?
SAMPLE
500YEN
たくさんの人に
読んでもらいたいんだろ？
SAMPLE
500YEN
だから　同人やってんだろ？
SAMPLE
500YEN
That's why you make doujinshi, isn't it?
SAMPLE
500YEN
だったら　どうして
このページなんですか？
SAMPLE
500YEN
But why did you have to pick that page?
これじゃ　さらし者だよ。
I'll be a laughingstock.
何で　そう思う？
Why do you think that?
だって　これ
未完成のページじゃないですか。
Because, well...
I didn't finish that page.
アハハ…
ペン入れ　間に合わなかったな。
Let me guess, you didn't have time to ink it?
だって…　入稿の前日になって
新しいネタ　思いついちゃって。
Well, I came up with a new idea for the story
a day before the final artwork deadline.
何だよ。　それで　できてた原稿
ボツにして　描き直したのかよ。
Yeah, so?
You scrapped what you'd finished
to start drawing new material.
But one day wasn't nearly enough time to do it,
（出海）けど　１日じゃ
全然　足りなくて→
だから　最後の方
下書きのままになっちゃって。
so the final product ended up
being un-inked drawings.
Right. So the second half was totally rushed.
そうそう。　後半なんか
完全に暴走しちゃってるよな。
だから　こんな看板
やめてください！
Then please stop using it as a billboard!
いや　このページでなきゃ駄目だ。
Nope. It has to be this page or nothing.
どうして　そんな　意地悪を…。
Why are you being so mean to me?
（恵）意地悪なんかじゃないよ。
He's not being mean.
恵さん？
Megumi-san?
From that point, right up to the end,
I never had a chance to catch my breath.
そこから　最後のページまで
息つく暇もなかった。→
すっごく　面白かった。
It was really interesting.
（男性）あの…。
（出海）ん？
Excuse me.
If you don't mind, may I take a look?
（男性）すいません。
見せてもらって　いいですか？
ぜひ
ご覧になっていってください！
By all means, browse all you want.
えっ　でも
この本は　男性向けじゃ…。
But this book isn't aimed at men.
（男性）どうも。
（出海）あっ。
Thank you.
（男性）１部　下さい。
（出海）えっ！？
I'll take one, please.
Thank you!
ありがとうございます！
どうですかー！　面白いですよー！（恵）ありがとうございます。
Give this a try!
Thank you.
It's very interesting!
（出海）ありがとうございました。
見ていってくださーい！
Thank you.
Come check it out!
（恵）こちら２部までと
なっております。
We've got two orders over here.
You can just take a look if you like!
お手に取るだけでもいいので！
（伊織）余計なことをしてくれたね。倫也君。
You just had to butt in, didn't you, Tomoya-kun?
（女性）１部　下さい。
（伊織）来年あたり→
One, please.
I was supposed to market this like crazy
next year through my own circle.
Thank you!
うちのサークルで　派手に
売り出すはずだったのにな～。
申し訳ありません！
完売でーす！
I'm sorry, everybody!
We're sold out!
I'm really...
本当に…　本当に→
truly...
thankful for all your support!
ありがとうございました！
[ﾏｲｸ]（アナウンス）ただ今をもちまして→
Comiket day two is now over.
コミックマーケット　２日目を
終了します。
≪英梨々！
Eriri.
えっ？
やっぱり　英梨々だ。
I thought it was you.
お前　さっき
出海ちゃんのサークルで→
You bought a book from Izumi-chan's
circle earlier, didn't you?
本　買ってただろ？
Just because you came without telling us
doesn't mean you have to be embarrassed.
黙って会場に来たからって
恥ずかしがることないだろ。
Playing the game for the first time in years
rekindled your passion for LitRhap, right?
この前　久しぶりにゲームして→
『リトラプ』熱が
ぶり返したんじゃないのか？
そんなんじゃない。
That's not why.
And Izumi-chan had nothing to do
with the attempt to take you.
あと　出海ちゃんは
引き抜きの件とは　関係ないぞ。
I know.
分かってる！
どうしたんだよ？
What's the matter?
何でもない。
Nothing.
Don't tell me it's nothing.
何でもないことないだろ。
英梨々…
お前　何か　怒ってるだろ。
Eriri, I can tell that you're mad about something.
この本　どうだった？
How was this book?
How was it?
どうだったって…
お前も　読んだんだろ？
You read it too, didn't you?
Then you know how it was, don't you?
だったら　分かんだろ？
うん　分かった。
Yeah, I know.
だって　倫也
すっごい　うれしそうだった。
I mean, you were over the moon about it.
ものすごく　真剣に売ってた。
You were so enthusiastic about selling them.
めちゃくちゃ　推してた。
You hyped it like crazy.
Of course I did.
当たり前だ。
すごいよ　出海ちゃん。
Izumi-chan's amazing.
いつの間に　こんなに成長して…。
She's come so far in such a short—
You've never reacted like that to any of my work!
あたしの本には
あんな反応　したことなかった！
倫也は　あたしの絵を見て
ドキドキしない…。
You don't get worked up like that
when you look at my artwork.
You don't go all-out trying to sell my books.
あたしの本を
本気で売ったりしない！→
何も　感じてくれない…。
You don't feel anything at all.
いや　ちょっと待てよ。
Hey, wait a second.
お前と出海ちゃんじゃ
全然　違うだろ！
You and Izumi-chan are totally different.
ジャンルも人気も
今の立ち位置もさ。
In genre, popularity,
and even where you are in life.
（英梨々）
じゃあ　あたしの方が　すごい？
You think I'm more amazing, then?
えっ？
ねえ　答えてよ！
Answer me!
Are my books better than hers?
あたしの本の方が
あの子の本より　すごい？
Do they make you want to do
whatever it takes to sell them?
何が何でも
売ってやろうって思う？
お前は…　俺が頑張らなくたって
売れるだろ。
But you...
Your books sell just fine without my help.
That's not an answer!
何も答えてない！
Tomoya, you haven't given me
a single straight answer all day!
倫也　さっきから
何にも　答えてくれない！
After every good-bye, my cheeks are always warm
bye-bye no ato samenai binetsu
w
And as I feel the wind against them, I always think
yokaze ni fukare kangaeru
Love? Hate? Hate? Love? Over and over
suki kirai kirai suki kurikaesu
What are you seeing in those eyes of yours?
sono hitomi ni utsutteiru no wa
Reality or something 2-D?
real sore tomo nijigen
Don't just say I look pretty like it's no big deal to me
tayasuku kawaii da nante iwanai de yo ne
Tomorrow, you'll rub your eyes and say "good morning"
ashita mo me wo kosutte ohayou wo itte
And talk about all sorts of pointless stuff
tawai mo nai koto takusan oshiete
And as we slowly grow closer together
sukoshizutsu chikadzuiteku kyori ni
What do I do? What am I usually like?
doushiyou jibun ja nai mitai da
This merry-go-round just never stops
merry-go-round ga tomaranakute
Spinning, spinning, the scenery blurs by
mawaru mawaru keshiki ga kawatteku
Like a colorful dream
colorful na yume wo miru
Throb, throb, I can feel them inside
dokudoku shite karadajuu wo
Going 'round and 'round, these feelings
meguru meguru kimochi
I still can't put them into words
mada kotoba ni dekinakute
Even though one word would be enough
hitokoto sore de juubun nanoni